Thank you!
ありがとう
Where did that come from?
何だ突然
Kobato liked yesterday's birthday
party, and it also made me... um...
昨日の誕生パーティー　小鳩も喜んでたし
俺も　何つうか　すげえ嬉しかった
Really happy.
So thank you!
だから　ありがとう
Qu-Quit saying that embarrassing stuff!
何恥ずかしいこと言ってんのよ
Don't call it embarrassing.
恥ずかしいとか言うなよ
Ahem. Well, um... This "birthday party"
thing turned out to be pretty nice.
まあ　そのう　何だ
誕生日パーティーというものはなかなかいいものだった
Let's all do our best to make
friends we can celebrate birthdays with!
私達も誕生日を祝えるような友達を作れるよう　頑張ろう
Yeah! This made me realize all over
again how cool it is to have friends.
今回改めて友達がいるっていいなっとわかったからな
マジで頑張ろうぜ
Let's seriously do this!
That's been my plan all along.
言われなくても最初からそのつもりよ
Your wish, Aniki.
御意です　兄貴
What's with you, Rika?
何だよ　理科
All right, then, let's keep
working on the school festival!
それじゃ　今日からまた学園祭に向けて頑張りましょう
Right, Kodaka-sempai?
ねえ　小鷹先輩
Y-Yeah, you're right...
そうだな
この時の俺にはまだ　覚悟がなかったのだ
At this point I wasn't
prepared to face things yet.
Even though deep down,
I knew what Rika was trying to say...
理科が何を言おうとしていたのか
本当はわかっていたのに
BE MY FRIEND
Be My Friend
知らないフリしたって
Shiranai furi shitatte
Be My Side
BE MYSELF
Zenbu kizuiteta yo
全部気付いてるよ
Mou ippo kimi no tonari ni ikou
もう一歩
君の隣に行こう
その手にだって届きそうさ
Sono te ni datte todokisou sa
"Haganai NEXT"
想像しちゃダメ
Souzou ijou da ne jetto koosutaa na mainichi
ジェットコースターな毎日
Hisshi de mae wo muite itsumo kakenuketa n da
引き締めて前を向いて
いつも駆け抜けたら
ずっと続きはしないね
Zutto tsuzuki wa shinai ne bokura no jikan wa
僕らの時間は今しかないから
Ima shika nai kara kono shunkan kizamitsukeyou
この瞬間刻みづけよう
Be My Friend
BE MY FRIEND
Shiranai furi shitatte
知らないフリしたって
Be My Side
BE MYSELF
Zenbu kizuiteta yo
全部気付いてるよ
Mou ippo kimi no tonari ni ikou
もう一歩
君の隣に行こう
受け止めるように
Te wo toreru you ni
Be My Friend
BE MY FRIEND
Miagete bakari datte
見上げてばかりだって
Be My Side
BE MYSELF
Akogareteru ima mo
憧れてる今も
Mou ikkai nando demo te wo nobasou
もう一回
何度でも手を伸ばそう
あの星だって届きそうさ
Ano hoshi datte todokisou sa
"My Childhood Friend Is Too Much of a
Battleground"
Yo.
チ～ス
Yahoo! Kobato-chan is seriously an angel!
小鳩ちゃんマジ天使
Let me lick you up, Kobato-chan! Lick, lick...
小鳩ちゃんぺろぺろさせて　ぺろぺろ
School Festival Ideas:
Festival day stuff (like a shooting gallery)
Magic show
Exhibit
Band
Eating contest
Endurance contest
Comedy routine
Cat café
What is a "cat café"? What is a "cat café"?
何だ　その猫カフェというのは
You don't know?
知らないですか
It's a café where you can play
with cats as you drink your tea.
猫と触れ合いながらお茶することができる喫茶店ですよ
Wh-What?!
何だと
Can such a paradise
exist in this rotten world?!
この腐った世界にそんなパラダイスが
I don't want to do an exhibit for the club too.
あたしこっちでも展示なんてやりたくないんだけど
Oh, yeah, you said you
were doing one for your class.
そういや　クラスでやるって言ってたな
"The History of Toya City," ri...
遠夜市の歴史
That's right!
そうよ
I suggested "The All-Knowing, Almighty
Goddess Kashiwazaki Sena Feature,"
あたしは「全知全能の女神柏崎星奈様特集」を提案したのに
but the girls were all bitterly against me.
女子から猛反対をくらって
It's pissing me off just
remembering those dumb girls!
思い出したらむかついてきたわ　あの馬鹿女ども
School Festival Ideas:
Festival day stuff (like a shooting gallery)
Magic show
Exhibit
Band
Eating contest
Endurance contest
Comedy routine
Cat café
Doujinshi sale
Leaving Meat's idiocy aside, an
exhibit doesn't seem fun, so let's not.
まあ　肉の馬鹿はともかく
展示は楽しくなさそうだからやめよう
And then... Take that!
あとは
Comedy
routine
ちょっと待って
Hey, wait! That's the best pick!
そりゃ最有力候補だろうが
Sure, for erasing.
消すほうのね
It's the correct decision.
適切な判断です
I believe that was appropriate.
妥当かと思われます
ククク　正しい選択であるぞ
Yes, she's made the right choice.
You guys...
お前ら
Hey, Kobato, should you be
skipping the middle school's festival?
そういや　小鳩
お前　中等部のほうの学園祭はいいのか
Isn't your class doing anything?
クラスで何かやらないの
What's your class presenting?
お前のクラスの出し物は何だ
ククク　我が眷属よ　貴様の知るよしもないことだ
My kindred, you shall never find out.
If you don't tell me, I won't
make you any pig-bone ramen.
言わないと豚骨ラーメン作ってやらないぞ
ククク　高貴なる闇の王レイシス·ヴィ·フェリシティ·煌を脅そうというのか
You would try to threaten Raysis Vi
Felicity Sumeragi, great ruler of the night?
Fool...
愚かな
And I'll eat all of yesterday's leftover beef.
昨日の肉の残りも全部俺が食う
Th-That's mean!
ずるい
Then just tell me.
だったら素直に言え
A-A movie.
映画
A movie?
映画ですか
That sounds fun!
面白そう
A movie, eh?
映画か
And? What will you be doing?
それで　お前は何をやるんだ
ククク　貴様には関わりな…
That is no concern of yo...
If you won't tell, you're cut off from gaming.
教えないなら　ゲーム禁止だ
...role...
…役
Huh? What did you say?
何だって
...ng role!
し…役
"Grole"?
役
The leading role, I said!
I gotta do the leadin' part now!
だから　主役
主役やらんといかへんくなってまったんじゃ
The leading role?!
主役
That's amazing, Kobato!
すげえじゃ　小鳩
- I want to see it! I so want to see that movie!
- Okay! Okay!
みたい　その映画超みたい
わかった　わかった
But Kobato, if you're the lead,
should you really be here?
っていうか　小鳩
主役がこんな所にいていいのか
So you skipped out on them...
ほっぽりだして来たのか
Kobato. It's an honor to
be chosen, so do a good job.
小鳩　せっかく選ばれたんだからしっかりやれよ
There are people who never get
picked to do anything in class, you know!
世の中には
クラスの中で何の役目ももらえないやつだっているんだぞ
Never?
何の役目も
Yup.
See? You got the chance,
so give it a try, Kobato.
せっかくの機会なんだから頑張ってみろうよ　小鳩
It's a really great thing to
have people who need you.
必要としてくれる人がいるっていうのも本当に凄いことなんだぜ
Mm-hmm.
よーし　それでこそ高貴なる闇の王レイシス·ヴィ·フェリシティ·煌だ
Now that's my Raysis Vi Felicity
Sumeragi, great ruler of the night!
Mm-hmm!
I shall be going, then!
じゃ　行って来るのだ
Yep, do your best.
頑張れよ
School Festival Ideas
Movie
Okay, we should make a movie, too!
よし　私達も映画を撮ろう
Rika saw this coming.
そう来ると思っていました
I have no objection.
私も異存はありません
Well, it was bound to happen this way.
まあ　当然の流れよね
I agree!
俺も賛成だ
All right, it's decided.
よし　決まりだな
Excuse me...
あのう
What is it?
何だ
Rika is fine with the decision,
but what will we make it about?
決定はいいんですけど　内容はどうするんですか
Leave the screenplay to me.
脚本は私に任せろ
No way! If we leave it to her,
it's 100% obvious that it'll be horrible!
絶対駄目
夜空なんかに任せたら
百パーセントひどいものになるに決まってるもの
What was that, Meat? You don't
believe in my magnificent taste?
何だと　肉
私の素晴らしいセンスが信じられないのか
Of course not!
当たり前でしょう
Considering your record
with the round-robin story...
夜空にはリレー小説の時の前科があるからな
Anyway, rest easy.
I'll take a lesson from my past,
とにかくこれまでの反省を生かし
and incorporate you
people's opinions as I write.
貴様らの意見も取り入れつつ書くから安心するがいい
So, let's get right down to it: any suggestions?
ということで早速だが
何か提案はあるか
No sexual assault, for starters.
とりあえず陵辱は禁止な
Wh-What?
何
いや　何じゃねえよ
Not the right reaction.
So she was really planning on it.
やっぱりやる気だったね
Ba-dum! I'm gracing you
with my presence, poopy-heads!
久しぶりに部室に来てやったぞ　うんこども
Since Maria-sensei is here too,
マリア先生も来たことですし
shall we start by pulling
together everyone's opinions?
まずは皆さんの意見をまとめましょうか
Okay, does anybody have any ideas?
よし　何かアイディアがある者はいるか
How about a story about a
transfer student who joins the class
ある日　クラスにやってきた転校生が
and is misunderstood and ostracized at first,
最初は誤解されて仲間はずれになるけど
but eventually becomes really popular?
やがてクラスの人気者になるってのはどうだ
I won't play any role that's not a juicy one.
あたしが演じるのは美味しい役でなきゃ駄目よ
I want to eat lots of juicy steak!
美味しいご馳走たくさん食べたいのだ
I would like to play a samurai.
わたくしはサムライの役がいいです
Rika thinks a slightly daring love
scene between two men is a must!
男同士のちょっぴり大胆なラブシーンは外せないと思います
Is it even possible to pull all that together?
Transfer student gets popular
Juicy Meat
Juicy steak
Samurai appears
Boy-on-boy action
これでちゃんとまとめられるのか
You watch: I'll make it the
masterpiece of the century.
私の力で世紀の大傑作にしてやろう
Look forward to it.
楽しみにしているがいい
何だ　こんな時間に
At this time of night?
Mikazuki Yozora
Tomorrow
Body: I'm going to
see a movie to get
some ideas. You
can come along if
you're free.
I don't *need* to go with anyone or whatever since all you do at a movie
is shut up and watch, but I figure if you have one you want to see, I'm
willing to go with you while I'm at it, that's all. If you're not interested
in movies, whatever, I'll just go by myself, so don't worry about it.
Her messages are always so rambling...
相変わらず回りくどいメールだな
But I guess it does make sense to
study a real movie before we start.
けど　確かに本物の映画を見て勉強するってのはありか
Okay, tomorrow the club can...
それじゃ明日は皆で
Mikazuki Yozora
No subject
oh don't tell the others cuz
there's no point in bringing a crowd
You typed that in a hurry, huh?
よっぽと急いで打ったんだな
"Don't tell the others," eh?
ほかへの連絡不要か
Mikazuki Yozora
Re: No subject
Understate.
Let's see...
小鷹
Kodaka!
Whoa, don't tell me you
seriously mean to keep up that look?!
お前　まさか　マジでその格好で通すつもりなのか
Of course I do.
当然だ
Let's go.
行くぞ
"Cinémathèque Toya"
So, what are we watching today?
で　今日は何を見るんだ
I haven't really picked one out.
We'll just pick from whatever's playing.
特に決めてない
上映しているものの中から適当に選ぶ
Isn't that pretty slapdash?
そんなでいいのか
This is how I always watch movies.
私はいつもこんな感じだ
How about this one?
これにするか
Mmmmm...
Seems kinda unexciting.
何か地味だな
No good for you?
いやなのか
Oh, n-no, this one's fine.
ああいや　いいよ　これで
C'est si bon!
セシボーン
C'est si bon?
C'est si bon.
C'est si bon!
- C'est si bon, c'est si bon.
- C'est si bon, c'est si bon...
Uh... was that useful?
あのう　参考になったか
Yeah, right! Idiot! I didn't
think it would be so disgraceful...
なるか　馬鹿
まさか　あんな破廉恥な内容だとは
Yeah...
だよな
B-By the way, Kodaka... do you...
want to do c-c'est si bon stuff too?
と　ところで小鷹もセシボーンのことをしたいと思うのか
Huh? What was that?
何だって
N-N-Nothing!
なんでもない
Okay! Let's have some tea
while we're out and about!
よし　せっかくだからお茶でも飲んで行こう
Hey, there's a café right there...
喫茶店ならそこに
No, there's another one
I really need to try. Let's go!
いや　どうしても確認しておきたい店がある　行くぞ
Covered in Kitties!
It's
OK to pet us!
Meow!
にゃん
"Meow"?
にゃんって
ほれ
Aw, you caught it!
捕まった
You really love cats, don't you?
お前　よっぽと猫が好きなんだな
There's no such thing as
a person who hates cats.
猫が嫌いな人間などいない
Don't you have one at home?
家では飼ってないのか
No, we live in an apartment.
うちはアパートだからな
Oh yeah, that's right.
そういえばそうだったな
But even if I weren't in an
apartment, I doubt I'd ever get a cat.
もっとも　アパートでなかったとしても
私が猫を飼うことはないだろうがな
Huh? Why not?
何でだ
Do you remember Night?
ナイトのことを覚えているか
C'mere, Night!
おいで　ナイト
Night!
ナイト
ナイト…
Night!
It's sad when someone suddenly disappears.
いきなりいなくなってしまうのは悲しいものだ
悲しい思いをするくらいなら
I don't want us to really
bond if they'll just make me sad.
深い絆なんていらない
適度にじゃれ合ってるだけでいい
I'm fine with just playing
together and not taking it too far.
Later, Kodaka. Look forward to my script.
じゃあな　小鷹
脚本楽しみにしているがいい
Sure.
何と言うか　今日はそのう
You know, today sort of made me feel like that.
あれだったな
"That"?
あれ
Like things were ten years ago.
10年前みたいだった
You're right. It did feel like
those days for me, just a little.
そうだな
確かにちょっとだけあの頃みたいな気がした
Well, see you, Kodaka.
それじゃあな　小鷹
King
Horse
脚本が完成したぞ
The screenplay is finished!
Frankly, I'm very pleased
with it. Accept it with respect!
正直会心のできだ
心して受け取るがいい
Now we can start filming!
これで撮影に取りかかりますね
Just what do you think you're doing?
で　何のつもり
ククク　わ　我が名はレイシス·ヴィ·何とか的な…
M-My name is Raysis Vi Something Something...
You faker!
この紛い物が
Not half bad.
やるじゃないの
This is way extreme.
マジぱないです
Did Yozora-sempai really write this?
これ本当に夜空先輩が
This is seriously good stuff. Are you a genius?!
マジでいいよ　これ
お前　天才か
I-Is it?!
そ　そうか
Hmph, naturally!
当然だ
Then it's decided: this will
be our script. Next is casting...
じゃあ　脚本はこれで決定ですね
では配役ですが
The cast is already set.
キャストならすでに決まっている
First off, I'll be the lead, Kuya.
まず主人公の空也は私だ
The transfer student, Kuya's former
best friend Hirotaka, is Kodaka.
空也のかつての親友で転校生の広孝に小鷹
O-Okay.
Sana, the class star who
opposes them to the end, is Meat.
この二人に最後まで敵対するクラスの中心人物
紗菜が肉
Nobuyuki, the timid boy who secretly
admires the manly Hirotaka, is Yukimura.
男らしい広孝にひそかに憧れている内気な少年伸行が幸村
All right...
はい
Serika, who always plays malicious
tricks on Kuya for being with Hirotaka,
広孝と一緒にいる空也に
悪質な嫌がらせを繰り返す芹香が理科
is Rika.
I see...
Mari, the little sister Kuya
doesn't get along with, is Maria.
空也と中が悪い妹の麻梨がマリアだ
Hmm... I don't really get it.
Cast:
Kuya... Me
Hirotaka... Kodaka
Sana... Meat
Nobuyuki... Yukimura
Serika... Rika
Mari... Maria
何だかよくわからない
Well? Isn't it perfect?
どうだ　ぴったりだろう
Objection!
異議あり
What, Meat? Is there some sort of problem?
何だ肉　何か問題でも
How come you're the
leading role and I'm the villain?!
何であんたが主役で　あたしが悪役なのよ
I read the script objectively
and made the logical choice.
客観的に脚本を読み　冷静に判断した結果だ
In particular, Sana is gorgeous
in appearance and the class star.
特に紗菜は華やかな見てくれのクラスの中心人物
Though it pains me to admit it, she
obviously has a lot in common with you.
しゃくだが貴様と重なる部分も多いだろう
Various circumstances have made her warped,
いろいろあって屈折してはいるが
but she's good at heart
and has lots of good scenes.
根はいいやつだし　見せ場も多い
I think it's quite a juicy role.
かなり「美味しい」役だと思うが
Now that you mention it, that might be true.
そう言われてみれば　そうかも
Then we'll use this cast for...
では配役はこれで
One moment, please!
待ってください
What, Rika? More objections?
何だ　理科　まだあるのか
Rika has no problem with casting
based on appearances and personalities.
外形や雰囲気で役を決めるのは問題ありません
But if we use that logic,
I think Kodaka-sempai is miscast.
でも
その理屈で言えば
小鷹先輩の役は違うと思います
Me?
俺の役
Nakagawa Hirotaka is a 17-year-old boy
中川広孝　17才　男
with a strong sense of justice and
an honest and stouthearted nature.
正義感が強く　実直且つ剛毅な性格
He's a popular, sociable guy
with a strong sense of humor.
社交的でユーモアのセンスもある人気者
He's smart and athletic,
and tall, and has manly features.
勉強も運動も出来　背が高くて顔も凛々しい
Yep, I'm a perfect fit.
俺にぴったりだ
It's obvious that Kodaka-sempai
doesn't fit the part!
こんなのどう考えても小鷹先輩に合ってないじゃないですか
Damn, she noticed.
気付かれたか
Wait, "noticed"?
気付かれたかって
True, Hirotaka and Kodaka are
about as different as you can get.
確かに小鷹と広孝では　イメージがあってないにも程があるわね
Because Big Brother isn't
cool at all on the outside!
お兄ちゃんは見た目は全然格好良くないからな
At...
- Yozora-sempai, why is Kodaka-sempai Hirotaka?
- At all... At all?
夜空先輩　どうして小鷹先輩が広孝なんですか
全然
全然か
Because...
だって
Kodaka was my childhood friend...
小鷹は私の幼なじみだから
Come to think of it, he was, wasn't he?
そういえばそうだったわね
Yes! Hirotaka and Kuya were childhood friends.
そうだ　広孝と空也は幼なじみだ
Therefore I chose my real-life
childhood friend Kodaka to be him.
だから私とリアル幼なじみの小鷹を広孝役に選んだ
What's weird about that?
それの何がおかしい
I-It's not weird, but...
べ　別におかしいとかじゃないけど
That means that if you aren't Kuya,
ということは　夜空先輩が空也でなければ
there ceases to be any reason for
Kodaka-sempai to be Hirotaka, correct?
広孝が小鷹先輩である理由もなくなるわけですよね
W-Well...
そ　それは
Why don't we decide on the casting by vote?
ここは一つ　配役を投票で決めるというのどうです
That's a good idea.
それがいいわね
Don't decide that on your own!
勝手に決めるな
Oh, dear, so you're not
confident you'll be chosen as Kuya?
おや　空也に選ばれる自信がないんですか
Fine. The results are obvious anyway.
いいだろう
どうせ結果など見えている
Excitement!
"Ballot Box"
Hirotaka... Yozora-sempai
Sana... Maria-san
Nobuyuki... Rika
Mari... Kodaka-sempai
Here are the results of the vote.
投票の結果
Kuya... Yukimura-kun
Hirotaka... Yozora-sempai
Sana... Maria-san
Serika... Sena-sempai
Nobuyuki... Rika
Mari... Kodaka-sempai
配役はこうなりました
Kuya
(lead)
Kusunoki
Yukimura
I'm... the leading role?
わたくしが主役ですか
Mikazuki
Yozora
Hirotaka
(best friend)
I can't believe this.
くっ 何たることだ
Yay! I'm a cool boss lady now!
Sana
(class boss)
Takayama
Maria
Yay! I'm a cool boss lady now!
私が偉いポスの女になったのだ
Kashiwazaki Sena
Serika
(likes Hirotaka)
Wh-Why?
な　何で
Nobuyuki
(admires Hirotaka)
Shiguma
Rika
Rika's playing the younger boy, then?
理科が少年役ですか
ちょっと待って
Hold on!
Why did this happen?!
何でこうなる
Hasegawa
Kodaka
Mari
(Kuya's little sister)
誰だよ　俺を妹役に押したやつは
Who picked me for the little-sister part?!
It was you?!
お前か
I-I thought it might be a
little fun, so I had no choice.
ちょっと面白そうかなって思ったんだから　しょうがないじゃない
What about that gave you no choice?!
どこにしょうがない要素がある
Plus, it wasn't just me! You got two votes!
それにあたしだけじゃないでしょう
2票入ってたんだから
もう一人は
Who's the other one?
Me!
はい
何でマリアが
Why?
Because Big Brother is always a big brother,
お兄ちゃんはな　いつもお兄ちゃんなので
so I thought it might be a nice change
to do a non-big-brother Big Brother!
たまにはお兄ちゃんじゃなくなったお兄ちゃんというのもいいなと思ったのだ
Hmm, our various ulterior motives
turned this into very strange casting...
皆さんの思わくが絡まりあった結果
よくわからない配役になってしまいましたね
But we can't actually do that, can we?
Why don't we vote one more time?
でもそれはさすがになしだろう
もう一度投票し直すってと
Kuya
( lead )
Kusunoki
Yukimura
Uh, Yukimura... Do your best in the lead, okay?
あのう　幸村
主役　頑張れよ
Yes, I shall work hard!
はい　頑張らせていただきます
で　俺の役どうしよう
Now what do I do about my part?
I'll change Mari to a little brother.
It won't harm the story any.
麻梨は弟に変更する
ストリー上不都合はないからな
What? Got a complaint?
何だ　文句でもあるのか
No, I... I'm just a little sorry.
いや　そのう　ちょっと　御免
Excuse me?
I-I ended up making more work for you.
余計な手間を掛けさせることになっちゃって
You're being creepy. Did you get
infected by some kind of evil bacteria?
気持ち悪いな　悪質な病原菌にでも感染したのか
You be quiet!
うるさいわね
This script was pretty good, so...
この脚本が割りとよかったから
Hmph! It's no trouble to change
a sister to a brother or whatever.
別に妹を弟にするくらい大した手間ではない
R-Really? Well, that's all right then...
そ　そう
だったら　いいんだけど
で　何だよ　これ
Hey, what the hell is this?
It's a totally different story now!
全然違う話になってるじゃないか
You're imagining things.
気のせいだ
No he's not! Who the heck is this "Kotaro" guy?!
気のせいじゃないわよ
Kotaro
何よ　この小太郎ってのは
Kuya's little brother.
空也の弟だ
I know that. What I'm asking is,
why are they suddenly twins?
そんなことはわかってるわよ
聞いてるのはなんで空也が双子になってるかってのことよ
Mari wasn't her twin!
麻梨の時は違ったでしょう
And the role is substantially more
important, too, with more screen time.
その上出番も重要性も大幅に増してますね
Plus Kuya and Hirotaka are talking
kind of coldly to each other now...
逆に広孝と空也のやり取りが何だか余所余所しくなってるし
Ah, yes. The truth is, Kuya and
Hirotaka weren't particularly close.
実は広孝と空也は別に仲良くなかったんだ
Huh? But they're best friends!
親友だろう
No. To Hirotaka, Kuya
was like a friend of a friend.
いや　違う
広孝にとって空也は　友達の友達的な関係だ
She was always with Kotaro,
小太郎と何時も一緒にいるから
so the three of them all
ended up hanging out, that's all.
とりあえず三人組みで過ごしていただけだ
Don't you feel bad for poor Kuya?
Why not let all three be friends?
空也が可哀想過ぎだろう
仲良し三人組でいいじゃないか
Kodaka. A "friend of a
friend" is not a "friend."
小鷹　友達の友達はな
友達じゃないんだ
What?
Their relationship isn't a
team of three. It's two plus one.
こいつらの関係は三人組ではなく
二人プラス一人なのだ
Well, that sounds familiar, but...
それは身に覚えあるけど
ちょっと待ってよ
Hold on a second! Why make
Kuya the odd one out, then?
だとしても　何で空也のほう一人にするのよ
If you make it Kotaro instead,
you don't have to change the story!
小太郎一人サイドにすれば
ストリーを変えなくても済むじゃない
I can't do that.
それは出来ない
Why not?!
何でよ
Because it's more natural for
him to get along with Kotaro.
小太郎と仲がいいほうは自然だからだ
I mean, Kodaka is playing Kotaro...
小鷹が小太郎役だし
Because Kodaka was your
childhood friend, you mean?
それって小鷹があんたの幼なじみだからってこと
Precisely!
そのとおりだ
That was forever ago. It doesn't matter now.
そんな昔のこと　今はどうでもいいでしょう
何だと　肉
What did you say, Meat?!
Wh-Why, you...
き　貴様
"D-Doesn't matter," you say?
ど　どうでもいいだと
Yes. It doesn't matter whether
you and Kodaka used to be friends.
ええ　あんたと小鷹が友達だったとか　どうでもいいのよ
What you need to do right now is
revise this script right, and you know it.
あんたが今やらなきゃいけないのは
脚本をちゃんと修正することでしょうが
How dare you! You don't know how I feel...
貴様　私がどんな気持ちで
I'm telling you it doesn't matter how you feel.
だから　んなことどうでもいいって言ってんの
Quit dragging the past around
with you and do the job you have now!
昔のことなんて何時までも引っ張ってないで
今やるべきことをやりなさい
Yozora...
夜空
You... If only you weren't here, I'd already be...
貴様さえ　貴様さえいなければ
今頃
柏崎星奈のアホ
Kashiwazaki Sena, you jerk!
おい　夜空
Hey! Yozora!
"If only you weren't here," huh?
貴様さえいなければ…か
I hate her, but you know, I've
never once wished she were gone.
わたし　あいつのこと大嫌いだけど
いなければいいって思ったこと一度もないんだけどな
Yozora?
夜空
What is it?
どうした
I left my bag in the club room.
部室にかばんを置いたままだったのだ
Oh.
そっか
Kodaka, who do you want to be
Hirotaka's old friend? Kuya or Kotaro?
小鷹はどっちがいいと思う
広孝と仲がよかったのは 空也か小太郎か
It doesn't matter which one,
as long as the story's interesting.
話が面白ければ　どっちでもいいよ
私は　小鷹と幼なじみがいい
I want you to be my old friend.
Hmm? What did you say?
何だって
Which is more important to you, Kodaka?
Our memories of ten years ago, or now?!
小鷹は10年前の思い出と今　どっちが大事なんだ
I can't make a choice like that!
選べねえよ　そんなの
はっきりしないな　お前は
You're not very clear.
What about you, then?
じゃあ　お前はどうなんだよ
Which is more important to you,
Yozora? Ten years ago, or now?
夜空は　10年前と今　どっちが大事なんだ
Ten years ago, of course.
そんなの　10年前に決まっている
Does that mean the present isn't important?
だったら今は大事じゃないのか
That's a toughie.
困ったな
See?
だろう
Yeah.
"The Moon Rises in the Sky"
"By: Mikazuki Yozora"
"Draft 3"
I like it!
いいじゃない
Hmph! This is a piece of cake for me!
私にかかれば造作もないことだ
Kotaro fits right into the original
story as a brother two years younger.
小太郎も二つ下の弟として
当初にストリーに自然に溶けこんでますね
Rika likes this one better, too!
Good work, Yozora-sempai.
理科もこっちのほうが好きです
お疲れ様でした　夜空先輩
Thank you for your hard work, Anego.
お勤めご苦労様です　姉御
S-Sure.
All right, I assume there
are no more complaints.
よし　これで文句はないな
So let's get down to filming this thing!
それでは　早速撮影に行くぞ
- Yeah!
- Let's do our best.
頑張ろうな
Let us be off.
参りましょう
It can't help but be a
masterpiece, since I'm in it.
あたしが出てる時点で名作間違いなしだけどね
Shut up, Meat.
黙れ　肉
これ　どこで見たような気がするな
I feel like I've seen this somewhere before...
光ったはずの星
Hikatta hazu no ano hoshi
迷った雲が邪魔して
Mayotta kumo ga jama shite mienaku naru
見えなくなる
Nani wo shinjitara ii?
何を信じたらいい
Fuantei sugiru sekai de
不安定すぎる世界で
Sodatta takaramono kowashikaketeta
育った宝物壊しかけてた
なくすのが怖くて
Nakusu no ga kowakute
不条理だって
Fujouri datte tameiki tsuki
ため息つき
どうにかどうで足掻いてた日々
Torikago de agaiteta hibi
Onaji sora wo miageteta n da bokura wa
同じ空を見上げてたんだ
僕らは
君の手を握った時
Kimi no te wo nigitta
toki nigirikaeshite kureta ne
握り返してくれたね
Tsunagatta kono te wa
donna hane yori tsuyoi n da
繋がったこの手は
どんな羽より強いんだ
Tsubasa nante nakutatte motto takaku toberu kara
翼だってなくったって
もっと高く飛べるから
Kitto ima nara daijoubu
きっと今なら大丈夫
大空輝く星を掴もう
Oozora kagayaku hoshi wo tsukamou
Oh, mademoiselle Yozora, you look so sad!
マドモアゼル夜空　とても切ないね
Oui! I think it's important for Yozora
to be more open with her feelings!
夜空はもっと素直になることが大切だと思います
That's right, you must openly
share your amour, like us!
そう　僕達のように素直にアムール伝えるのさ
とてもジュテームだよ　ステファ二ー
I je t'aime you so much, Stéphanie!
I je t'aime you too, Jonathan!
わたしもジュテームだわ　ジョナサン
"Stray Cats Overheat"
Next time: "Stray Cats Overheat."
次回　「迷い猫　オーバーヒート」
僕の股間も　オーバーヒート
My loins are overheating too!
C'est si bon! C'est si bon!
セシボーン　セシボーン